shahharlik@gmail.com harlikshah.github.io HARLIK SHAH linkedin.com/in/harlikshah

657-319-5457 | California, USA github.com/harlikshah

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduate MS CS candidate with **2+ years** of **work experience** as a Software Developer at BNP Paribas along with **2 internships** – Summer 2020 at FaceFirst & working as a Fall 2020 intern at TNP. Seeking full-time positions starting May 2021 as Software Developer.

EDUCATION

California State University Fullerton, Los Angeles, California

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science

Dwarkadas J Sanghvi College, Mumbai, India

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Computer Engineering

SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, C#, .NET, C++

Databases: MS SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Cloud Firestore

Web Tech: React, Angular 4, TypeScript, MEAN, jQuery, HTML, CSS

Architecture: REST, MVC, SPA, Microservices

Cloud: Google Cloud, AWS, Lambda, EC2, S3, Sagemaker

Big Data: Hadoop, MapReduce, Spark, Hive

Libraries: TensorFlow, OpenCV, scikit-learn, NumPy **Tools:** Gitlab, Jira, Jenkins, Swagger, Postman, Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Network Pro, Fullerton, California

Software Engineer Intern - Fall 2020

Aug 2020 - Present

May 2021

May 2017

GPA: 3.83/4

CGPA: 9.1/10

- Creating an application monitoring dashboard to track the issues, logs and tasks using React, Nodejs, REST API and MySQL
- Automating scripts which parses data from internal tool into the databases and resulting in saving 55 hours/week of manual work

FaceFirst, Los Angeles, California

Software Engineer Intern - Summer 2020

May 2020 - July 2020

- Developed Single Sign-On (SSO) feature using React, MongoDB, Material UI and deployed it into production for Home Depot client
- Implemented a unit test script in C++ for comparing ground truth and clustering output datasets which has increased by 66%
- Integrated load balancing into an application to support large images retrieval per second out of 25M for Banco Azteca client
- Trained 8M datasets consisting of VGG2, MS Celeb, & Wiki in order to improve face detection by 87% accuracy with face masked

California State University Fullerton

Graduate Research Assistant

Sept 2019 - Present

- Researched and analyzed Solar panel configurations with an improvement in the performance of partial shading panels by 82%
- Working with different models such as Random forest, SVM, Naive Bayes classifier and Decision Trees consists of large datasets

BNP Paribas, Mumbai, India

Software Developer

June 2017 - July 2019

- Developed a global accounts receivable application which create invoices of UK, NAR regions using Java, Angular 4 & MSSQL server
- Reduced the time & effort by 60% in automating the process of creating vast volume of manual invoices using Python & MongoDB
- Led the development of critical settlement & unsettlement transaction modules consists of 1.2 million monthly transactions
- Designed optimized SQL queries and complex stored procedures for faster execution and retrieval of data into the database
- Followed the Agile scrum methodology by performing code reviews, unit testing, CI/CD, documentation & deploying into prod
- Mentored three interns on domain knowledge of the application as well as Agile practices, Git, Angular and database architecture

Cerelabs, Mumbai, India

R&D Artificial Intelligence Intern

June 2016 – July 2016

- Researched and developed a handwriting recognition project using TensorFlow, OpenCV and Intelligent Word Recognition (IWR)
- Scanned doctor's prescriptions into computer-generated text format using IWR & implemented string word comparison

PROJECTS

Finary

React, Firebase, Postman, REST API, Material UI, Alpaca API, IEX cloud, HTML, CSS, Figma, Gitlab, Git

Developed an investing social network website for allowing people to trade, learn to invest and incubated by Harvard and Mozilla labs

Caption Generation for Image frames

Python, TensorFlow, Inception V3 model, OpenCV, CNN, LSTM, Jupyter, MS COCO

Generated the captions from image frames & formed three meaningful sentences based on captions by achieving accuracy of 74.67%

Facial recognition for student attendance

MongoDB, JavaScript, Angular 4, Python, Face API, OpenCV

Built a web application wherein students can mark their attendance by the face and implemented CNN for feature extraction of faces

Diamond buy and sell trading

JavaScript, phpMyAdmin, PHP, jQuery, MySQL, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3

Created buy/sell diamond trading website in which users can post their demands online in Newsfeed without any broker commissions

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Felicitated with **BRAVO** spot award at BNP Paribas for an outstanding performance and delivering robust solution into production
- Received 2nd rank with honors amongst 150 students in computer science department during my undergraduate college
- Attended various hackathons like HackUCI, Cal Hacks & ACM board committee for Computer Science department at CSU Fullerton